No, see, the way it's set
now, the gyro's too sensitive.
If you want to prioritize
the visual tracking,
you gotta give yourself a little
more room in these parameters.
Okay, but won't it lag like crazy
if she makes any sudden moves?
I guess you'll just have to trust that the
learning program and the
optimizer can deal with it.
How much longer, guys?
Our lunch break's almost over!
Let's just save this as the
default setting and hope it works.
Hey, uh, Yuki, can you hear okay?
Yep, I hear you loud and clear.
Good, all right.
I'm firing up the lens now,
so it might get bright.
Let me know when you can see perfect,
and I'll lock that setting in.
Fire away!
Hold it!
Okay, you're ready to go.
Last thing, I installed stabilizers,
but they're kind of janky.
Try not to make any sudden moves, okay?
Ah, thanks, Kirito!
Thank you.
That's why I can't hear you.
The story of the story is
the beginning of the song.
I'm going to connect with you.
Oh, give it for my way.
Wow!
Your school's ginormous!
I know, right?
I'm sorry I couldn't
show you around first,
but the lunch break's almost over
and we don't want to be late.
Nah, that's okay.
I'm just excited to check
out your class. Sweet.
Then let's head to the faculty room
and introduce you to my teacher.
What's wrong?
It's the one part of school I don't miss.
Go into the faculty room.
Don't worry.
The teachers here aren't
your typical teachers.
They're cool.
Excuse me!
Me too!
I just wanted to make
sure it was still alright.
Sure, I'm fine with it.
And what's the name of the student
who'll be joining us today?
Oh, um, Yuki!
Yuki Kono, sir!
Uh, okay.
Miss Kono, you're welcome in
my class any time you want.
Although, we start
Akutagawa's alori today.
Unless you stick with it to the
end, you won't get the point!
Yes, sir, thank you very much.
See you in class.
What's that, Miss Yuki?
Hey, how'd you know my name?
Oh, no, she was using my last name there.
Oh, right.
Uh, guys, meet Yuki Kono.
She's in the hospital right
now and can't leave her room.
So instead, she'll be
attending our class like this.
Nice to meet you.
I can only hang out for?
a little while though.
Nice to meet you.
Hey there, my name's Cait. Oh, hi.
Hey, nice to meet you too.
Please stand. Bow. Be seated.
All right then, class.
Please open your textbooks to page 97.
We'll be reading Alori
by Ryunosuke Akutagawa.
Let's see, who'll read it for us?
Yuki Kono, would you do the honors?
Me?
Problem?
No, sir.
I can do it.
Yuki, are you up for this?
I might not look it,
but I have read before.
When Ryohei was eight years old,
construction on the light railway
between Odawara and Atami began.
Every day, he would head to the
outskirts of town to watch the progress.
It wasn't the construction of
it that fascinated him so much.
It was the sight of the lorries
transporting the soil which drew him.
There were two laborers aboard the lorry,
standing behind the
soil they'd just loaded.
Since the lorry was headed down the
mountain, it didn't need anyone to push it.
So as the chassis swung, and the
sleeves of the laborer's coats flapped,
and the narrow rails
bent under the strain,
Ryohei would gaze longingly at these
sights and wish he could be a laborer too.
Or at the very least, be able to
ride on it with them, if only once.
I love listening to you read Yuki.
Hey, have you had a
chance to tour the school?
If not, we could show you around.
Take it easy, guys.
Hey, wanna go to a soccer match?
Thanks, guys.
You're the best.
Now that was fun.
I know, right?
Thanks for making today happen. Asuna.
Really, I had a blast.
I'm never.
gonna forget today. Ever.
Well, of course you won't.
The teacher said you could come back again
if you want.
Oh, modern Japanese is
third period tomorrow.
You don't
want to miss that.
Yeah. Okay, what's next?
Is there anything else
you want to do or see?
Oh, um,
I guess there is one?
place I'd like to go. Where?
It's so pretty here huh?
Just look at that sky!
Yeah.
Hey!
Are your folks cool with
you staying out so late?
You've been hauling me around all day!
Don't you worry about it!
I send them a text!
And it's fine! Well!
Where do you want to go next?
Yuki!
Go left!
Hey, are we in Tsukimidai yet?
Yeah.
Next corner, there's a white house.
Can you stop there?
Yuki, this is your house, huh?
Mm-hmm.
I never thought I'd get
the chance to see it again.
Thanks for bringing me out here.
And for everything.
Do you want to go inside?
Nah, this was enough.
Come on, let's head back
before your folks get worried.
No, it's okay.
We can stay a little longer.
Me and my family, we only got to
live here a little over a year.
And the weird thing is, I can
remember every day so clear.
My sister and me used to play in
the yard, running around and around.
We had barbecues, and we even built
these bookshelves with our dad.
Good times.
Lucky you.
Yeah.
They're gonna tear it all down, though.
Really? Why?
My aunt wants to either put a
convenience store here, or maybe sell it.
No way.
That's why I wanted to come here,
so I could see it one more time.
Well, I know how you can save it. How?
You're 15 now, aren't you?
When you turn 16, find someone
you love and marry him.
That way you'll have
someone around who will
keep this house from ever being torn down.
You got the craziest ideas.
I don't think there's anyone
I want to marry, though.
Oh, yeah?
But you and June make a cute couple.
God, no.
That guy's so immature.
Let's see.
Who should I marry?
Oh, I know. You.
The only thing is, if you marry
me, you'll have to be the wife.
I mean, the other way around, my name'd
be Yuki Yuki, and that'd be weird.
I can't imagine what my mom
would say. I know. I'm kidding.
Besides, you already got someone lined up.
Oh, yeah, I guess.
Still, you should be careful.
I get the feeling he's not
living in the real world either.
Not like me, but, you know.
I can't thank you enough, Asuna.
Just to stay in my old house again?
You don't know how happy that makes me.
Back when we lived here, I remember
we'd go to church to pray and stuff.
And Mom used to always say
this to me and my sister.
God would never put us through all this
suffering if He didn't
think we could bear it.
It didn't make me feel any better, though.
Instead of quoting the Bible,
what I really wanted was for Mom to
talk to us like, well, like a mom.
But you know, after seeing her old
house again, I think I get it now.
The words didn't matter.
It was the feeling behind those words.
She was praying for me so I
wouldn't feel sorry for myself,
so I could be strong to the
end, and now I finally get it.
I'm the same.
See, I...
I haven't understood my mom, either.
I can't hear what she's
really trying to tell me.
She can't seem to hear me.
Remember what you told me?
That sometimes you have to
fight to get your point across?
How can I get to be strong? Like you?
Me?
I'm not strong. No way.
Oh, yes, you are.
You're not like me.
When you stand up to someone, you don't
flinch or let them intimidate you.
Nothing seems to scare you at all.
It's like second nature for you.
Yeah, I don't know.
When I was living in the real
world, or you know what I mean,
most of the time I was faking it.
It's like I thought I had
to act cheerful because I
didn't want to make my mom
and dad feel sad for me.
Yuki.
You want to know what I think in the end?
So what if I'm just acting?
If I get to spend more time smiling,
even if it's fake, what's
the big deal, am I right?
I mean, it's not like I got
a whole lot of time left.
And it'd be a shame to waste whatever
I do got by moping around all the time.
So now I say exactly
what I feel to everyone.
And if they got a problem
with that, who cares?
At least they spoke my mind.
And maybe even got a
little closer to them.
You're right.
That's the reason we're here today.
Why?
Why we're so close after only a few days?
It's all because of you.
Nope.
That wasn't because of me.
It's because even after I ran away
from you, you tracked me down.
Look, how about you try talking
to your mom, like you did to me?
If you try telling her how you feel,
maybe you'll get through to her.
Don't worry. You can do it.
You're way stronger than me. Honest.
Yuki...
You hit me with everything you had.
That's how I knew I could trust
you with everything I had.
In the end, it worked out
for both of us, didn't it?
Yes, it did.
Thank you so much, Yuki.
If you try telling her how you feel,
maybe you'll get through to her.
Don't worry, I know you can do it!
Come in.
You're late again.
I'm sorry.
Well, if you're hungry, you'll have to
make do with whatever's in the fridge.
Oh, and don't forget, the deadline for
your transfer application is due tomorrow.
Make sure it's filled out by morning.
Actually, about that …
We need to talk, Mother.
Well, what is it?
I can't really explain it here.
Okay then, where shall we go?
The virtual world.
It'll only be for a little while,
and you're going to have to use this.
Don't be ridiculous!
If you can't tell me what this
is about like a normal person,
I don't want to hear it.
But you don't understand!
It's the only way I can explain!
It's just five minutes!
Mom, please!
There's no other way to tell you what
I'm thinking and how I'm feeling, honest!
I can't tell you any of that here!
Just this once!
Mom, all I want is for
you to see my world!
Five minutes.
But, no matter what you say,
I have no intention of allowing you
to attend that school again next year,
understood?
Also, once you're done, you
will fill out that application.
Okay.
So how do I use that thing?
Just sit back and relax.
Once I turn it on, it'll automatically
connect you to my subaccount in the game.
After you're in, wait for me.
I'm turning it on now.
Link, start!
This is so bizarre.
Seeing a strange face mimic
what I do is unsettling.
And this body, it's so light.
Oh, that's normal.
That particular avatar's weight
setting is about 90 pounds or so.
Feels lighter than your real body, huh?
That is so rude.
I do not appreciate what you're implying.
That's interesting.
Your face here looks
just like your real one.
Well, yes.
Actually, I take it back.
Your real face is puffier than this one.
Oh, now who's being rude?
I look the same here as I do there.
Well, I'm here. Now what?
You don't have much time left.
Follow me, Mom.
You see?
It looks just like it.
I have no idea what you mean.
All I see is some old cedar gro -
Doesn't it bring back memories?
Of the house that grandma and grandpa had?
I really loved their place in Miyagi.
It was magical.
Remember that Obon holiday when I was 12?
You, Dad, and Koichiro went to
the Yuki family Kampan in Kyoto,
and I went to Miyagi by myself.
I remember.
When I got there, I apologized to
them that you couldn't be with us.
I felt bad you couldn't
visit our ancestors' graves.
I wanted to, but that year, the Yukis
were having an important memorial service.
No, Mom, I'm not blaming you or anything.
In fact, you know what Grandpa said?
He said not to fuss because he
and Grandma were so proud of you.
Huh?
You left this village,
went to university, became a
scholar and got your work published.
It made him so happy to see you make
a name for yourself in the world!
And then he told me
something I'll never forget.
That someday you might get tired from all
the hard work you do and
need a break from it.
And if that day ever came,
he said he wanted to make sure the house
and the mountain were always there.
That he'd guard them.
To give you a place to come home to.
if you needed it.
I didn't understand it then!
But now, after everything
that's happened to me?
I think I finally do.
Life isn't just about doing
the things that make you happy?
It's also about finding a way to live.
Where the happiness of
everyone around you?
fulfills you too.
Somehow,
I want to figure out how to live a life
that makes everyone around me happy.
I want a life that lets
me be there for the people
I care about when they
need someone to lean on.
That's all I want.
Mother, I'll study and work hard,
but I want to keep going
to the school that I love.
What is this?
This is crazy.
I'm not really crying.
Mom, you can't hide it when
you're sad in this world.
When you cry, you cry,
just like in real life.
Such an annoying world.
Asuna, are you determined to live the
kind of selfless life you spoke of?
Fine.
If that is what you want, you'll have to
be strong enough to carry that burden.
So make sure you go to college.
And for that, you'll have to get better
grades this trimester and next year.
Really?
Then I can stay?
That's up to you.
You'll have to prove yourself.
Do your best.
Thanks, Mom. I will.
Thank you, Yuki.
Here I go.
Thank you
for
listening.
So I am now.
Never to leave.
I'm sure you're. There is so the
before you meet. I'm sure. Oh, you are.
I'm sure you're.
You are.
I can't. You are.
That's the.
You can't.
I. I'm.
I'm.
I'm. I'm.
I don't know if I can't hear anything.
I can't hear anything.
I can't hear
anything.